## G GIRIBALAN

28/97, 1<sup>st</sup> Street, P. P. Garden, Aminijikarai, Chennai- 600029. (0) +9884157102

E-mail: giribalan1985@gmail.com

## **OBJECTIVE**

To pursue a challenging career in IT sales & service and be a part of an organization that gives me scope to enhance my knowledge and skill in order to scope with the latest technological trends that enables me to serve for the organizational growth

## Career Summary

A self motivated professional with around 8 years of proven success in Operations, Marketing, Project Implementation & Management, Client Relationship management in Retail, industry. Distinction of having Product Specializations in Barcode Scanners, Printers, Mobile computing devices, RFID Scanners, Plotter, Wireless infrastructures, Electronic weighing Systems etc. In Engineering, Electrical and IT environment. Strong in strategy planning, setting goals, motivation, Team work for achievement, study & share new techs, Analytical, competition strength and weakness. Demonstrated skill of charting out customer retention plans for achieving unparalleled loyalty and service quality levels. Well conversant in the management of After Sales Service, Co- ordination between Oustomer and Head office for various specifications/ requirements.

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## Assi*stant Manager - Business Development* (since Jun 2016) M/s. SAI SRI AUTOMATION & ENGINEERING PVT. LTD.

## Key areas of responsibilities:

- Project Implementation, Pre-Sales, Business Development to Retail, Industries, Corporate and Institutions
- Responsible for prospect generation, understanding of clients requirements, suggesting them
  the right solution and the products/services, preparation of techno-commercial proposals,
  handling negotiations and sales closure
- Develop and manage pre sales activities & Generate the Cold call
- · Sales of total IT Infrastructure Solutions
- Complete project development including H/W and S/W
- Co-Ordinate with customers for product ( HHT, wifi, scanner, RFID, Printer & Scanner) .
- Chennai branch Sale & service team supports.

#### Key activities/ Achievements.

- Responsible for the sales process right from the initial sales call till the effective implementation of the projects.
- Successfully implemented the Bar-coding and wireless projects in the industrial / retailing sectors thus providing complete IT infrastructure solutions to the verticals.
- Sales of Both Bar coding Hardware & Software like Asset Management, Retail Management etc., thus providing one-stop solutions to the clients.

Area Covered : Tamilnadu, Andhra, Karanataka
Reporting To : General Manager in AIDC(Kolkata)

## Senior Business Development Executive (Sep 2014 to May 2016) W.s. HOLOFLEX LIMITED - Kolkata.

#### Key areas of responsibilities:

- Project Implementation, Pre-Sales, Business Development to Retail, Industries, Corporate and Institutions
- Responsible for prospect generation, understanding of clients requirements, suggesting them
  the right solution and the products/services, preparation of techno-commercial proposals,
  handling negotiations and sales closure
- Develop and manage pre sales activities & Generate the Cold call
- Sales of total IT Infrastructure Solutions
- Complete project development including H/W and S/W
- Co- Ordinate with customers for product ( HHT, wifi, scanner, RFID, Printer & Scanner).

### Key activities/ Achievements.

- Responsible for the sales process right from the initial sales call till the effective implementation of the projects.
- Successfully implemented the Bar-coding and wireless projects in the industrial / retailing sectors thus providing complete IT infrastructure solutions to the verticals.
- Sales of Both Bar coding Hardware & Software like Asset Management, Retail Management etc., thus providing one-stop solutions to the clients.

Area Covered : Tamilnadu, Andhra, Karanataka
Reporting To : General Manager in AIDC(Kolkata)

# Techno Commercial Executive AIDC (Oct 2012 to Sep 2014) Ms/ PROTOCOL LABELS INDIA Pvt Ltd.

## Key areas of responsibilities:

- Project Implementation, Pre-Sales, Business Development & Service support to Retail, Industries, Corporate and Institutions
- Develop and manage pre sales activities & generate the cold call
- Sales & Service of total IT Infrastructure Solutions
- Complete project deployment including H/W and S/W
- Co-Ordinate with customers for product ( HHT, wifi, scanner, RFID, printer) & PO

#### Key activities/ Achievements.

- Responsible for the sales & service process right from the initial sales call service call till the effective implementation of the projects.
- Successfully implemented the Bar-coding and wireless projects in the industrial / retailing sectors thus providing complete IT infrastructure solutions to the verticals.
- Sales of Both Bar coding Hardware & Software like Asset Management, Retail Management etc., thus providing one-stop solutions to the clients.

Area Covered : Tamil nadu, Andhra, Kerala, Karanataka

Reporting To : Manager for South India

## Branch Support Engineer AIDC (Apr 2011 to present) Ms/INTELLICON Pvt Ltd

- Working as Residential Engineer at Nokia India Pvt Ltd at Sriperumadur.
- Given the onsite service support for more than 650 Higher end and Industrial Zebra Barcode printer. Independently handle the whole Shif
- Install and Configure wireless Printer, wireless Terminals.
- · Recommend and implement complete Technical Support solutions
- Product Suggestion to Nokia Engineer For Implement New Project

Area Covered : Tamilnadu, Andhra.

Reporting To : Branch Manager

# Sr. Customer Support Engineer (March 2006 to Apr 2011) M/s Amont Software & Equipment Pvt Ltd

- Managing and Handling the service & Sale actives
- Doing business development. Motivate the team to achieve their product wise targets
- · Handling the End To End Services, Product of Printers, Plotters & Scanner.
- Appoint the Service & Sales Executives and trained them in various products of Plotters, Printers & Routers.
- Handled the team to achieve their targets.
- Event Management
- Trouble Shoot and Solve the Network and hardware Problem

## Customer Support Engineer (July 2005 to Feb 2006) M's WORLD SPACE SATEILLITE RADIO

- Managing and Handling all sale actives.
- Oustomer relationship & Management.
- Event Management

### ACADEMIC EDUCATION

B. C. A - Bachelor Computer Application Madres University

M. D. A. Magter of Business Administration Management University

M. B. A - Master of Business Administration Manormaniam University

### Technical Education

D. E. E. E - Diploma in Electrical and Electronics Engineer S. R. M Polytechnic, Chennai D. A. V. CD- Diploma in Audio, Video & CD (TECHNOLOGY) RAJA ELECTRONICS INSTITUTE, Chennai - 600 114.

## Computer Proficiency

C. H. D Computer Hardware Services

ADVANTAGE PRO. Chennai - 600 034

MS office Word, Excel, Power point.

**Communications** : Microsoft Active Sync 11.0 **Designing software** : Corel draw, Photoshop, flash, Maya

(Using the software to our project PPT)

Operating Systems : Windows 98, XP, Vista, Windows 7& Windows 8.

Getting Certificate from **ZEBRA** for Zebra Barcode printer, **TECHNICAL CERTIFICATE** 

## Languages known

Tamil, Telugu, English, Hindi, Malayalam

### LEISURE

Basket Ball, Volley Ball & Athletes.

## Personal Details

Fathers Name R. Gopal

Date of Birth 22- 05- 1985

Marriage status Married

## DECLARATION

I expect a congenial and fairly free atmosphere for functional responsibilities as I enjoy now. Freedom of action and recognition of merit, good culture are expected to facilitate better achievement in my new assign

(Giribalan.G)